<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>anumittal.in/</title>
   
   <link>https://anumittal.in</link>
   <description>Personal blogs</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> Anu Mittal</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Akademy 2018, Vienna</title>
	  <link>//akademy-vienna</link>
	  <author>Anu Mittal</author>
	  <pubDate>2018-10-02T18:40:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//akademy-vienna</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <!--[Campus][akademy-campus]-->
<p><img src="/assets/images/campus.JPG" alt="Campus" width="100%" />
This year Akademy (an annual world summit of KDE) was held in a beautiful city Vienna, Europe during the late second and third week of August.</p>

<p>Akademy like every year had many interesting talks and bofs scheduled</p>

<!--[Akademy talks][akademy-talks]-->
<p><img src="/assets/images/AnuKDE.JPG" alt="talks" width="100%" />
My talk was scheduled on the first day of the event where I talked on Kontainerzing KDE.</p>

<!--![Presentation on Docker][akademy-docker]-->
<p><img src="/assets/images/dockerPPT.png" alt="dockerPPT" width="100%" />
The talk began with a general introduction to Containerization technologies and why we need it. Followed by how we have used Docker and flatpak at KDE.</p>

<p>The presentation is available <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1LdtW9T0pT2t6RS0c0X7qbXzhjT1v8GvFPARuBtlCGoY/edit?usp=sharing">here</a></p>

<p>Summary of each day at Akademy:
Day 1: <a href="https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/12/akademy-2018-day-1">https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/12/akademy-2018-day-1</a>
Day 2: <a href="https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/12/akademy-2018-day-2">https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/13/akademy-2018-day-2</a>
Day 3: <a href="https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/14/akademy-2018-monday-bof-wrapup">https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/14/akademy-2018-monday-bof-wrapup</a>
Day 4: <a href="https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/14/akademy-2018-tuesday-bof-wrapup">https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/14/akademy-2018-tuesday-bof-wrapup</a></p>

<!--[Best part of Akademy][akademy-humans]-->
<p><img src="/assets/images/akademy2018.jpg" alt="humans" width="100%" />
It was a great experience to meet active contributor of KDE all around the globe and learn more about the insights. During the KDE India bof, we discussed how we can get more contributors on board and get the most out of conf.kde.in 2019.</p>

<p>Looking forward to seeing more contributors in India in the conf.kde.in next year.</p>

<p>PS. Call for Hosts for Akademy 2019 is still open. For more, check <a href="https://dot.kde.org/2018/05/15/akademy-2019-call-hosts">here</a></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>LinuxChix Meet up experience!</title>
	  <link>//linuxchix-meet-up-experience</link>
	  <author>Anu Mittal</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-09-17T18:40:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//linuxchix-meet-up-experience</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr"  trbidi="on">Hi all,<br /><br />Today I got an opportunity to celebrate Linux's 26th anniversary (17th September 1991) with the LinuxChix India team (<a href="http://india.linuxchix.org/">http://india.linuxchix.org/</a>).<br /><br />I gave a talk on:<br /><br /><ul ><li>Unix, GNU, and &nbsp;Linux's history&nbsp;</li><li>And shared my experience using Linux, Ubuntu, and Kubuntu</li></ul><br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xtJqJqHepf8/Wb6-glYazhI/AAAAAAAAsBk/2PU2-f13wPwio2a_7c3o1oYGIHG2L9BsgCLcBGAs/s1600/linux.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" data-original-height="720" data-original-width="1107" height="257" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xtJqJqHepf8/Wb6-glYazhI/AAAAAAAAsBk/2PU2-f13wPwio2a_7c3o1oYGIHG2L9BsgCLcBGAs/s400/linux.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><br />It was a great interactive session. We shared some thoughts about:<br /><br /><ul ><li>SSH's working</li><li>Linux&nbsp;distributions</li><li>Flavours of Ubuntu</li><li>Kubuntu, KDE Plasma 5 and KDE frameworks,&nbsp;</li><li>Linux file system&nbsp;</li><li>Kernels and its role</li><li>Various Linux Commands</li></ul><br />I would like to thank Shivani Bhardwaj and Priyal Trivedi for organising the meetup and Amit Kumar for introducing me to the team.<br /><br />Link to the slides of my talk:<br /><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B9XiOPGG2l_vcTNNcEVhVjV1RnM/view?usp=sharing">https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B9XiOPGG2l_vcTNNcEVhVjV1RnM/view?usp=sharing</a><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><span id="goog_181807117"></span></div></div>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Akademy 2017 -  A wonderful experience</title>
	  <link>//akademy-2017-wonderful-experience</link>
	  <author>Anu Mittal</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-08-16T20:30:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//akademy-2017-wonderful-experience</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     Hola Amigos!<br> Akademy 2017 was such a great experience, that I would love to share with you all in this post. <br> For those who are unaware about Akademy, it’s an annual world summit of KDE (Please refer https://akademy.kde.org).
<br>  This year, Akademy was held in Almeria, Spain.
<br> It features a 2-day conference with presentations on the latest KDE developments, followed by 4 days of workshops, Birds of a Feather (BoF) and coding sessions. <br> There are so many interesting talks given by some real tech enthusiasts, who are amiable and super cool. It is a great opportunity to meet people in person whom you have been communicating just knowing their IRC nickname. <br> So, as mentioned it started with some really interesting presentations on Plasma desktops, Plasma mobile, Ruqola, digiKam, WikiData, GCompris, KIO library, Calligra, KDE neon, Slimbook, Translating Challenges, and many more. We were fortunate to have Robert Kaye and Antonio Larrosa as our keynote speaker. These presentations were followed by BoF sessions and Workshops.  <br>I conducted a workshop on Qt Quick Control 2, Paul Brown had some awesome stuff to share on what data should be visible to a viewer who visits your site or uses your product. Parallelly there was a BoF session, where the team brainstormed on Plasma mobile and Plasma vision. <br> [ https://twitter.com/anu22mittal ] <br> It was such pleasure to meet Valorie, Aleix Pol, Albert, Lydia, John Samuel, David, Timothee, Vasudha, Jonathan and so many more active contributes of KDE. <br> [Memories of Akademy 2017] <br> Now, How is KDE Akademy different than conf.kde.in? <br> I have been a part of KDE India conference held in Jaipur in 2016 [conf.kde.in]. Which looked like this: <br> When you see this, you find so many students, keen to know about foss and KDE community. <br> All are budding developers with some spark and unexplored ideas in their mind. So such type of conference held by KDE in India help these unexplored ideas to come into execution by using and developing features in the various software build by KDE developers. <br> Where as when you look at these bunch of developers here in this picture: <br> This is the group photograph of Akademy 2017 attendees. They are the backbone of all softwares in KDE. <br> I would like to thank KDE for giving me this opportunity. It has added great experience and wonderful memories to my journey of foss development  <br>  [Hostel, Food, Location @ Akadmey] <br> Also, guys please help make KDE apps and Plasma easier to use, more convenient and accessible. <br> Support [#Randa2017](https://dot.kde.org/2017/08/08/randa-meetings-2017-its-all-about-accessibility).
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>FOSSASIA SUMMIT 2017 and KDE</title>
	  <link>//fossasia-summit-2017-and-kde</link>
	  <author>Anu Mittal</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-06-20T01:13:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//fossasia-summit-2017-and-kde</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr"  trbidi="on"><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-r_g5JvVgUn4/WU4TGIlu9VI/AAAAAAAAcR0/xcC72kS1--Y-q3fhADg74FzmvFMdJ-LDwCLcBGAs/s1600/fossasia17.jpeg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" data-original-height="622" data-original-width="1600" height="155" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-r_g5JvVgUn4/WU4TGIlu9VI/AAAAAAAAcR0/xcC72kS1--Y-q3fhADg74FzmvFMdJ-LDwCLcBGAs/s400/fossasia17.jpeg" width="400" /></a></div><br /><br />I got an opportunity to represent KDE in FOSSASIA 2017 held in mid-March at Science Center, Singapore. There were many communities showcasing their hardware, designs, graphics, and software.</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vVVbsE9UQ5o/WUhfTDCe4yI/AAAAAAAAcJo/HKioA6KmvkISrgdJFQC573HLBA282lFLgCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20170317_105342.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" data-original-height="1600" data-original-width="949" height="320" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vVVbsE9UQ5o/WUhfTDCe4yI/AAAAAAAAcJo/HKioA6KmvkISrgdJFQC573HLBA282lFLgCLcBGAs/s320/IMG_20170317_105342.jpg" width="188" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;Science Center, Singapore</td></tr></tbody></table><div style="text-align: justify;">I talked about KDE, what it aims at, what are the various programs&nbsp;that KDE organizes to help budding developers, and how are these mentored. I walked through all the necessities to start contributing in KDE by introducing the audience to KDE Bugzilla, the IRCs channels, various application Domains, and the SoK(Season of KDE) proposal format.&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-rlC23nTTlyk/WUhfmGZJhaI/AAAAAAAAcJs/7edf0RKXHdg7dXwzurQo-UYfMzuMyF-nwCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20170318_155222.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" data-original-height="900" data-original-width="1600" height="180" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-rlC23nTTlyk/WUhfmGZJhaI/AAAAAAAAcJs/7edf0RKXHdg7dXwzurQo-UYfMzuMyF-nwCLcBGAs/s320/IMG_20170318_155222.jpg" width="320" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;">Then I shared my journey in KDE, briefed about my projects under Season of KDE and Google Summer of Code. The audience were really enthusiastic and&nbsp;curious to start contributing in KDE. I sincerely thank FOSSASIA for giving me this wonderful opportunity.</div><br />Overall&nbsp;working&nbsp;in KDE has been a very enriching experience. I wish to continue contributing in KDE and also share my experiences to help the budding developers to get started.<br /><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div></div>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>conf.KDE.in 2016, Jaipur</title>
	  <link>//confkdein-2016-jaipur</link>
	  <author>Anu Mittal</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-03-10T18:52:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//confkdein-2016-jaipur</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr"  trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-JpjhlbLwJs8/VuFerN_6O_I/AAAAAAAAFfA/boZZ7SW0_Z4/s1600/KDE.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="265" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-JpjhlbLwJs8/VuFerN_6O_I/AAAAAAAAFfA/boZZ7SW0_Z4/s400/KDE.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><br />5th-6th March 2016:<br />Thank you KDE India for inviting us to share our experience with 250+ budding developers and spreading the knowledge we have acquired during our projects. It was beyond just a meetup, we made many new friends and also learnt a lot from each other. I would also like to thank LNMIIT for hosting such an amazing conference and for the flawless hospitality. The event was very well planned and executed. I hope the participants find all the talks and workshops effective and implement them someday.<br />Though the conference was of only two days but I was able to create hundreds of &nbsp;memories as it was my first FOSS project, first talk, and my first ever meet up of such kind.All the speakers had something inspirational to the audience in their talk, who seem to be enthusiastic too, they had a keen interest in knowing more about things and asked many questions out of curiosity. The evening workshops were the most active session wherein the participants were demonstrated how to use KDE software and implement Git commands.And after the day's activity, the chit-chat sessions at the dinner table were the best part where we were able to know more about each other as how each of us worked on innovative ideas and made through it. At the end of the conference director of LNMIIT presented each of us with a beautiful momento.<br />It was an unforgettable experience.I got to learn lots of things from this conference. I would like to thank each and every person connected with this conference for making it so special and would like to encourage all of my blog readers to participate in such events and contribute to FOSS projects. These are few things you cannot afford to miss. All you need is &nbsp;1.) interest 2.) idea 3.) amazing organization like KDE and bang! You are almost there.<br />Good Luck! ;)<br /><br /><br /></div>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
