<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>anumittal.in/</title>
   
   <link>https://anumittal.in</link>
   <description>Personal blogs</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> Anu Mittal</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Panel discussion at HackSingapore</title>
	  <link>//HackSingapore-Panel</link>
	  <author>Anu Mittal</author>
	  <pubDate>2023-10-14T01:30:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//HackSingapore-Panel</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>On 20th May 2023, I got an opportunity to be a panelist at one of Singapore’s most active hackathon community known as HackSingapore.</p>

<h4 id="what-was-the-topic-of-the-panel">What was the topic of the panel?</h4>
<p>The topic of the panel was “Importance of soft-skill in Engineering” where the focus was on the importance of soft skills such as communication, collaboration, and leadership in technical roles in the tech industry where I as a speakers shared examples of how these skills have been crucial to my success.</p>

<h4 id="why-was-i-keen-to-talk-about-the-topic">Why was I keen to talk about the topic?</h4>
<p>My motivation for discussing this topic stems from my personal and professional experiences. As a Staff Engineer at Circles, I have a bachelor’s degree in computer science and a passion for open source. I have contributed to KDE and participated in Google Summer of Code, which gave me the chance to speak at various conferences around the world, such as in Spain, Singapore, and India. There, I learned the value of networking and connecting with people from different backgrounds and perspectives. I have also worked in several startups, where the dynamic environment and the “break fast, grow fast” mentality taught me the importance of soft skills like communication and collaboration. Moreover, I believe in giving back to the community and helping others learn and grow. I am an active contributor to WWCode and kodeco, where I use my soft skills to mentor and support fellow developers.</p>

<h4 id="as-a-staff-engineer-on-the-ic-track-how-have-soft-skills-played-an-important-part-in-your-day-to-day">As a staff engineer on the IC track, how have soft skills played an important part in your day-to-day?</h4>
<p>Soft skills are essential for my day-to-day work as a staff engineer on the IC track. I interact with various stakeholders, such as business teams, product managers, designers, and more, who have different backgrounds and knowledge levels. I need to adjust my communication style accordingly to ensure effective collaboration across teams with different skill sets.
For example, when I talk to a technical person, I can use more technical terms and details. But when I talk to a business person, I need to focus on the ROI and benefits in business terms. This way, I can tailor my communication to the level of understanding and context of each stakeholder.</p>

<p>Another important part of my role as a staff engineer is creating a safe space where team members can share their ideas and innovations without fear of judgment. This requires strong leadership skills, which are also soft skills.</p>

<p>One of these leadership skills is engaging in a technical and constructive feedback loop with team members. I encourage open discussions, provide feedback, and listen to different perspectives. This helps foster a culture of continuous improvement and innovation. Effective feedback and communication also help team members grow and develop, which ultimately leads to the success of the team as a whole.</p>

<p>In summary, soft skills are vital to my role as a staff engineer. They help me navigate diverse stakeholders, adapt my communication style, and create an environment that promotes collaboration, innovation, and growth. By improving these soft skills, I can lead and contribute to the success of my team and the projects we work on.</p>

<h4 id="how-important-has-it-been-to-network-with-people-in-the-same-organization-and-also-outside-attending-conferences-giving-talks">How important has it been to network with people in the same organization, and also outside (attending conferences, giving talks)?</h4>
<p>Networking has been vital for my professional growth and development. Within my organization, networking has helped me connect with people with different skill sets, such as data analysts, operations experts, business professionals, product managers, and designers. This wide network has enabled me to grow vertically and horizontally, expanding my knowledge and capabilities. Interacting with experienced professionals has also given me valuable insights and perspectives, helping me learn faster and avoid reinventing the wheel. My depth of understanding the architecture helps me come up with solutions, but my breadth of experience helps me find the right solution. It’s a subtle but key distinction!</p>

<p>Additionally, networking within my organization has improved my efficiency and productivity. By knowing the right people, I can quickly navigate through the organization, finding the relevant points of contact and getting things done more effectively. Building connections within my team has also helped create a high-performance culture, where collaboration and shared expertise flourish.</p>

<p>Outside my organization, attending conferences and meetups has been key in connecting me with brilliant minds from various industries. These interactions have allowed me to exchange ideas, challenge boundaries, and learn from different approaches to problem-solving. Giving talks at conferences and mentoring others has given me an opportunity to contribute to the community and give back. This experience has not only increased my confidence but also deepened my own understanding as I prepare, teach, and answer questions from the audience.</p>

<p>Networking has helped me forge valuable connections, access diverse perspectives, and accelerate my learning curve. Both within and outside my organization, networking has enhanced efficiency, teamwork, and continuous development. I strongly believe in the power of networking and its ability to create meaningful opportunities for personal and professional advancement.</p>

<h4 id="what-is-one-piece-of-soft-skills-advice-would-you-give-to-folks-interested-in-becoming-a-staff-engineer">What is one piece of “soft skills” advice would you give to folks interested in becoming a staff engineer?</h4>
<p>My soft skills advice for aspiring staff engineers is to embrace the shades of grey. Recognise that complex engineering scenarios are not black and white.</p>

<p>As a staff engineer, your role is not to pick what feels right or make decisions based on personal preferences. Instead, your responsibility is to look at the bigger picture and evaluate trade-offs. Think iteratively, weighing the pros and cons of different approaches. Consider the perspectives and needs of all stakeholders involved.
Building the foundation for the future requires a balanced approach. It’s important to avoid rejecting ideas or solutions without proper consideration. Instead, analyze and weigh the risks involved, considering the potential impact and outcomes.
By embracing the shades of grey, you can navigate complex engineering challenges with a mindset that seeks to find the best solution for the current situation. This approach helps you make informed decisions, build consensus, and effectively lead your team towards successful outcomes.</p>

<p>As a staff engineer, your soft skills are essential for collaborating with others, managing expectations, and guiding technical decision-making. Embracing the complexity and nuances of each situation will help you excel in this role and make a positive impact in your engineering journey.</p>

<p>I am thankful for my career path, the companies and teammates I have worked with so far, where I got the safe environment to develop both my hard (technical) and soft skills. It was a great experience leading a panel discussion and answering some of the questions from the audience.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Akademy 2019 - Milano, Italy</title>
	  <link>//Akademy-2019</link>
	  <author>Anu Mittal</author>
	  <pubDate>2019-09-13T13:30:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//Akademy-2019</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Another successful event of Akademy held in Milan, Italy this year(2019). As always, I feel it was a great catch up with the fellow KDE contributors. Contributors not just limited to technical domain but also from various other domains like Translation, Promotion, documentation, etc.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/Akademy2019/groupphoto.jpg" alt="Akademy 2019 group photo" /></p>

<p>As <a href="https://conf.kde.org/en/akademy2019/public/events">scheduled</a>, day1 - 7th Sept and day2 - 8th Sept had a lot of talks on the on-going and upcoming projects. One of the most important talks of the event was “KDE’s Goals” hosted by Lydia, Neofytos and Ivan, which was an interactive session on what have we achieved in the last year and what will be KDE’s next year’s goals.</p>

<p>After the last year’s goal revolving around Privacy, Onboarding, Usability and Productivity, there was voting for picking the new goals. The list of prospective goals and selected ones are listed <a href="https://phabricator.kde.org/tag/goal_setting_2019/">here</a>
<img src="/assets/images/Akademy2019/Akadmey.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>This year, I was not only an attendee and a speaker but also volunteered for session chairing, video operations, and helped at the info desk.
<img src="/assets/images/Akademy2019/volunteer.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/Akademy2019/Labplot2019.png" alt="Talk on Labplot" />
<img src="/assets/images/Akademy2019/labplot2.4.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Like every year, we had a <a href="https://akademy.kde.org/2019/program">week</a> of BoFs (Bird of Feather), Workshops, Meetings, Daytrip and Training.</p>

<p>There is great news from one of the BoF on KDE India. For all the buddy developers or open-source enthusiast, conf.kde.in will be held from 17th January 2020 to 19th January 2020, in Delhi, India. The call for papers is open and you can find more details on <a href="https://dot.kde.org/2019/10/17/confkdein-coming-back-2020">conf.kde.in</a></p>

<p>I am thankful to KDE for sponsoring my travel and congratulate the team on successfully hosting such a productive conference to gather contributors from all around the globe.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/Akademy2019/SocialEvent.png" alt="SocialEvent" width="50%" />
<img src="/assets/images/Akademy2019/Valorie.png" alt="favorite lady" width="50%" /></p>

<p>As always, I would like to encourage my readers to start or keep contributing to open source projects and to get started with KDE you can read my <a href="https://anumittal.in/KDE-Season-of-KDE">previous blog</a> or <a href="https://community.kde.org/Get_Involved">getting involve page</a></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Akademy 2018, Vienna</title>
	  <link>//akademy-vienna</link>
	  <author>Anu Mittal</author>
	  <pubDate>2018-10-02T11:40:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//akademy-vienna</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <!--[Campus][akademy-campus]-->
<p><img src="/assets/images/campus.JPG" alt="Campus" width="100%" />
This year Akademy (an annual world summit of KDE) was held in a beautiful city Vienna, Europe during the late second and third week of August.</p>

<p>Akademy like every year had many interesting talks and bofs scheduled</p>

<!--[Akademy talks][akademy-talks]-->
<p><img src="/assets/images/AnuKDE.JPG" alt="talks" width="100%" />
My talk was scheduled on the first day of the event where I talked on Kontainerzing KDE.</p>

<!--![Presentation on Docker][akademy-docker]-->
<p><img src="/assets/images/dockerPPT.png" alt="dockerPPT" width="100%" />
The talk began with a general introduction to Containerization technologies and why we need it. Followed by how we have used Docker and flatpak at KDE.</p>

<p>The presentation is available <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1LdtW9T0pT2t6RS0c0X7qbXzhjT1v8GvFPARuBtlCGoY/edit?usp=sharing">here</a></p>

<p>Summary of each day at Akademy:
Day 1: <a href="https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/12/akademy-2018-day-1">https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/12/akademy-2018-day-1</a>
Day 2: <a href="https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/12/akademy-2018-day-2">https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/13/akademy-2018-day-2</a>
Day 3: <a href="https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/14/akademy-2018-monday-bof-wrapup">https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/14/akademy-2018-monday-bof-wrapup</a>
Day 4: <a href="https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/14/akademy-2018-tuesday-bof-wrapup">https://dot.kde.org/2018/08/14/akademy-2018-tuesday-bof-wrapup</a></p>

<!--[Best part of Akademy][akademy-humans]-->
<p><img src="/assets/images/akademy2018.jpg" alt="humans" width="100%" />
It was a great experience to meet active contributor of KDE all around the globe and learn more about the insights. During the KDE India bof, we discussed how we can get more contributors on board and get the most out of conf.kde.in 2019.</p>

<p>Looking forward to seeing more contributors in India in the conf.kde.in next year.</p>

<p>PS. Call for Hosts for Akademy 2019 is still open. For more, check <a href="https://dot.kde.org/2018/05/15/akademy-2019-call-hosts">here</a></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>LinuxChix Meet up experience!</title>
	  <link>//linuxchix-meet-up-experience</link>
	  <author>Anu Mittal</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-09-17T11:40:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//linuxchix-meet-up-experience</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr"  trbidi="on">Hi all,<br /><br />Today I got an opportunity to celebrate Linux's 26th anniversary (17th September 1991) with the LinuxChix India team (<a href="http://india.linuxchix.org/">http://india.linuxchix.org/</a>).<br /><br />I gave a talk on:<br /><br /><ul ><li>Unix, GNU, and &nbsp;Linux's history&nbsp;</li><li>And shared my experience using Linux, Ubuntu, and Kubuntu</li></ul><br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xtJqJqHepf8/Wb6-glYazhI/AAAAAAAAsBk/2PU2-f13wPwio2a_7c3o1oYGIHG2L9BsgCLcBGAs/s1600/linux.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" data-original-height="720" data-original-width="1107" height="257" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xtJqJqHepf8/Wb6-glYazhI/AAAAAAAAsBk/2PU2-f13wPwio2a_7c3o1oYGIHG2L9BsgCLcBGAs/s400/linux.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><br />It was a great interactive session. We shared some thoughts about:<br /><br /><ul ><li>SSH's working</li><li>Linux&nbsp;distributions</li><li>Flavours of Ubuntu</li><li>Kubuntu, KDE Plasma 5 and KDE frameworks,&nbsp;</li><li>Linux file system&nbsp;</li><li>Kernels and its role</li><li>Various Linux Commands</li></ul><br />I would like to thank Shivani Bhardwaj and Priyal Trivedi for organising the meetup and Amit Kumar for introducing me to the team.<br /><br />Link to the slides of my talk:<br /><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B9XiOPGG2l_vcTNNcEVhVjV1RnM/view?usp=sharing">https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B9XiOPGG2l_vcTNNcEVhVjV1RnM/view?usp=sharing</a><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><span id="goog_181807117"></span></div></div>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Akademy 2017 -  A wonderful experience</title>
	  <link>//akademy-2017-wonderful-experience</link>
	  <author>Anu Mittal</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-08-16T13:30:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//akademy-2017-wonderful-experience</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><strong>Hola Amigos!</strong><br /><br />
<strong>Akademy 2017</strong> was such a great experience, that I would love to share with you all in this post. <br /> For those who are unaware about Akademy, it’s an annual <a href="https://akademy.kde.org">world summit of KDE</a>.
<br /> This year, Akademy was held in <strong>Almeria, Spain</strong>.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Akademy features a 2-day conference with presentations on the latest KDE developments, followed by 4 days of workshops, Birds of a Feather (BoF) and coding sessions.
<br />There are so many interesting talks given by some real tech enthusiasts, who are amiable and super cool. It is a great opportunity to meet people in person whom you have been communicating just knowing their IRC nickname.<br /><br />So, as mentioned it started with some really interesting presentations on <em>Plasma desktops, Plasma mobile, Ruqola, digiKam, WikiData, GCompris, KIO library, Calligra, KDE neon, Slimbook, Translating Challenges</em>, and many more. We were fortunate to have <strong>Robert Kaye</strong> and <strong>Antonio Larrosa</strong> as our keynote speaker. These presentations were followed by BoF sessions and Workshops.<br /><br /><strong>I conducted a workshop on Qt Quick Control 2</strong>, <em>Paul Brown</em> had some awesome stuff to share on what data should be visible to a viewer who visits your site or uses your product. Parallelly there was a BoF session, where the team brainstormed on Plasma mobile and Plasma vision.<br /><br />It was such pleasure to meet <em>Valorie, Aleix Pol, Albert, Lydia, John Samuel, David, Timothee, Vasudha, Jonathan</em> and so many more active contributes of KDE.<br />[Memories of Akademy 2017]
<strong>How is KDE Akademy different than conf.kde.in?</strong><br />I have been a part of <a href="conf.kde.in">KDE India conference</a> held in Jaipur in 2016. Which looked like this: <br /> When you see this, you find so many students, keen to learn about <em>FOSS and KDE community</em>. <br /> All are budding developers with some spark and unexplored ideas in their mind. So such type of conferences held by KDE in India help these unexplored ideas to come into execution by using and developing features in the various softwares build by KDE developers. <br /> Whereas, when you look at these bunch of developers here in this picture: <br /> This is the group photograph of Akademy 2017 attendees. They are the backbone of all softwares in KDE, expert and deeply involved in contributing in KDE.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><br /><em>I would like to thank KDE for giving me this opportunity. It has added great experience and wonderful memories to my journey of foss development</em> <br /><br />PS. Help make KDE apps and Plasma easier to use, more convenient and accessibl by supporting <a href="https://dot.kde.org/2017/08/08/randa-meetings-2017-its-all-about-accessibility">#Randa2017</a></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>FOSSASIA SUMMIT 2017 and KDE</title>
	  <link>//fossasia-summit-2017-and-kde</link>
	  <author>Anu Mittal</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-06-19T18:13:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//fossasia-summit-2017-and-kde</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr"  trbidi="on"><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-r_g5JvVgUn4/WU4TGIlu9VI/AAAAAAAAcR0/xcC72kS1--Y-q3fhADg74FzmvFMdJ-LDwCLcBGAs/s1600/fossasia17.jpeg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" data-original-height="622" data-original-width="1600" height="155" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-r_g5JvVgUn4/WU4TGIlu9VI/AAAAAAAAcR0/xcC72kS1--Y-q3fhADg74FzmvFMdJ-LDwCLcBGAs/s400/fossasia17.jpeg" width="400" /></a></div><br /><br />I got an opportunity to represent KDE in FOSSASIA 2017 held in mid-March at Science Center, Singapore. There were many communities showcasing their hardware, designs, graphics, and software.</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vVVbsE9UQ5o/WUhfTDCe4yI/AAAAAAAAcJo/HKioA6KmvkISrgdJFQC573HLBA282lFLgCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20170317_105342.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" data-original-height="1600" data-original-width="949" height="320" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vVVbsE9UQ5o/WUhfTDCe4yI/AAAAAAAAcJo/HKioA6KmvkISrgdJFQC573HLBA282lFLgCLcBGAs/s320/IMG_20170317_105342.jpg" width="188" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;Science Center, Singapore</td></tr></tbody></table><div style="text-align: justify;">I talked about KDE, what it aims at, what are the various programs&nbsp;that KDE organizes to help budding developers, and how are these mentored. I walked through all the necessities to start contributing in KDE by introducing the audience to KDE Bugzilla, the IRCs channels, various application Domains, and the SoK(Season of KDE) proposal format.&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-rlC23nTTlyk/WUhfmGZJhaI/AAAAAAAAcJs/7edf0RKXHdg7dXwzurQo-UYfMzuMyF-nwCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20170318_155222.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" data-original-height="900" data-original-width="1600" height="180" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-rlC23nTTlyk/WUhfmGZJhaI/AAAAAAAAcJs/7edf0RKXHdg7dXwzurQo-UYfMzuMyF-nwCLcBGAs/s320/IMG_20170318_155222.jpg" width="320" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;">Then I shared my journey in KDE, briefed about my projects under Season of KDE and Google Summer of Code. The audience were really enthusiastic and&nbsp;curious to start contributing in KDE. I sincerely thank FOSSASIA for giving me this wonderful opportunity.</div><br />Overall&nbsp;working&nbsp;in KDE has been a very enriching experience. I wish to continue contributing in KDE and also share my experiences to help the budding developers to get started.<br /><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div></div>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>conf.KDE.in 2016, Jaipur</title>
	  <link>//confkdein-2016-jaipur</link>
	  <author>Anu Mittal</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-03-10T10:52:00-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//confkdein-2016-jaipur</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr"  trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-JpjhlbLwJs8/VuFerN_6O_I/AAAAAAAAFfA/boZZ7SW0_Z4/s1600/KDE.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="265" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-JpjhlbLwJs8/VuFerN_6O_I/AAAAAAAAFfA/boZZ7SW0_Z4/s400/KDE.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><br />5th-6th March 2016:<br />Thank you KDE India for inviting us to share our experience with 250+ budding developers and spreading the knowledge we have acquired during our projects. It was beyond just a meetup, we made many new friends and also learnt a lot from each other. I would also like to thank LNMIIT for hosting such an amazing conference and for the flawless hospitality. The event was very well planned and executed. I hope the participants find all the talks and workshops effective and implement them someday.<br />Though the conference was of only two days but I was able to create hundreds of &nbsp;memories as it was my first FOSS project, first talk, and my first ever meet up of such kind.All the speakers had something inspirational to the audience in their talk, who seem to be enthusiastic too, they had a keen interest in knowing more about things and asked many questions out of curiosity. The evening workshops were the most active session wherein the participants were demonstrated how to use KDE software and implement Git commands.And after the day's activity, the chit-chat sessions at the dinner table were the best part where we were able to know more about each other as how each of us worked on innovative ideas and made through it. At the end of the conference director of LNMIIT presented each of us with a beautiful momento.<br />It was an unforgettable experience.I got to learn lots of things from this conference. I would like to thank each and every person connected with this conference for making it so special and would like to encourage all of my blog readers to participate in such events and contribute to FOSS projects. These are few things you cannot afford to miss. All you need is &nbsp;1.) interest 2.) idea 3.) amazing organization like KDE and bang! You are almost there.<br />Good Luck! ;)<br /><br /><br /></div>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
